export default Dpe8 = [

    {
        question: "1. Which is the device used to measure electric current ?",
        options: ["Ammeter",
            "Voltmeter",
            "Resistor",
            "voltameter"],
        correct_option: "Ammeter"
    },


    {
        question: "4. The SI unit of electric current is",
        options: ["Watt",
            "Ampere",
            "Volt",
            "Ohm"],
        correct_option: "Ampere"
    },
    {
        question: "5. The SI unit of electric energy is",
        options: ["Volt",
            "Ampere",
            "Watt",
            "KWH"],
        correct_option: "KWH"
    },
    {
        question: "6. In the formula œÅ = Ra/l , the letter 'a' stands for",
        options: ["Length",
            "Specific resistance",
            "Cross-sectional area",
            "Material radius"],
        correct_option: "Cross-sectional area"
    },

    {
        question: "7. The obstruction to the flow of current is called.",
        options: ["Current",
            "None",
            "Voltage",
            "Resistance"],
        correct_option: "Resistance"
    },
    {
        question: "8. The positively charged ions in an electrolytic solution are called",
        options: ["Anion",
            "Cation",
            "Anode",
            "Cathode"],
        correct_option: "Cation"
    },
    {
        question: "11. If the length and radius of a conductor are both halved , the resistance become",
        options: ["Doesn't change",
            "4 times",
            "Halved",
            "Doubled"],
        correct_option: "Doubled"
    },
    {
        question: "12. 1 Coulomb / 1 second is the same as",
        options: ["1 - Ampere",
            "1 - Ohm",
            "1 - Volt",
            "1 - Coulomb"],
        correct_option: "1 - Ampere"
    },

    {
        question: "13. An example of Ohmic conductor",
        options: ["Copper",
            "Silicon",
            "Nichrome",
            "Germanium"],
        correct_option: "Copper"
    },
    {
        question: "14. Find out the correct statement ?",
        options: ["Both are right",
            "In parallel connection , the same potential difference gets applied across each element",
            "Both are wrong",
            "In series connection , the same current flows through each element"],
        correct_option: "Both are right"
    },


    {
        question: "17. In a electrolytic cell , the electrode connected to the positive terminal of the battery is called the",
        options: ["Cation",
            "Anode",
            "Anion",
            "Cathode"],
        correct_option: "Anode"
    },
    {
        question: "18. What are the units of resistivity ?",
        options: ["Ohm",
            "Volt",
            "Ohm meter",
            "Ampere"],
        correct_option: "Ohm meter"
    },
    {
        question: "19. Which is not suitable for domestic electric circuit ?",
        options: ["Switch is connected in series to the electric appliance",
            "All the electrical appliances are connected in parallel",
            "Switch can be connected in series or parallel with electrical appliances",
            "Switch is connected parallel to the electric appliance"],
        correct_option: "Switch can be connected in series or parallel with electrical appliances"
    },
    {
        question: "20. In house the properties of fuse wire is",
        options: ["To prevent damages due to over loading",
            "Both To prevent damages due to over loading & Consists of thin wire of low melting point",
            "None",
            "Consists of thin wire of low melting point"],
        correct_option: "Both To prevent damages due to over loading & Consists of thin wire of low melting point"
    },
    {
        question: "21. A 10W LED bulb is used 10 hour's per day.Find the electric energy consumed in 10 days",
        options: ["1000 KWH",
            "2 KWH",
            "None",
            "1 KWH"],
        correct_option: "1 KWH"
    },
    {
        question: "22. The product of potential difference and the current is called",
        options: ["Electrical potential",
            "Magnetic flux",
            "Electric power",
            "Resistance"],
        correct_option: "Electric power"
    },
    {
        question: "23. Find the incorrect statement /statements from the following",
        options: ["Resistance of a conductor depends on material",
            "Resistance of a conductor is independent of area of cross-section",
            "None",
            "Both Resistance of a conductor depends on material & Resistance of a conductor is independent of area of cross-section"],
        correct_option: "Both Resistance of a conductor depends on material & Resistance of a conductor is independent of area of cross-section"
    },
    {
        question: "24. What is an electric discharge between two clouds or between cloud and earth ?",
        options: ["Sunlight",
            "Thunder",
            "Rain",
            "Lightning"],
        correct_option: "Lightning"
    },
]